Varun Bharadwaj

Phone: India: +91 9481512364
Email: varunbharadwaj00@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bhrdwjvarun/

Objective

To add maximum value to the organisation I work for and gain valuable insight and experience in the industry. Also, make substantially positive contributions towards the growth of an organisation with my knowledge and dedication towards work. I also have a passion to code and work on cutting edge technologies in the software industry.

Education

Visvesvaraya Technological University (VTU)

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science; CGPA: 8.3/10

Bengaluru, India 2018-2022

Experience

Alvolved Technologies

Deep Learning Intern

Bengaluru, India March 2021 - Present

- Worked on projects such as Real-time Helmet Detection for Bengaluru Traffic Police and Human Pose Detection to calculate the parameters required for GAIT Analysis.
- Hands on experience in training models and making predictions on custom data.
- Worked on frameworks such as Pytorch, YOLOv5, Keras and Tensorflow.

Stige Remote
Data Analyst Intern May 2021 - June 2021

- Learnt SQL in depth while working on advanced topics like window functions
- Learnt to visualise real time data using Matplotlib, Seaborn
- Performed day to day operations on data such as Data Cleaning and EDA

Sparks FoundationRemoteData Science and Business AnalystApril 2021

- Implemented ML algorithms on real world data to make predictions and building models
- Learnt to perform EDA on data using Tableau

Projects

COVISCAN (Web App) Link

Input a chest xray and our app will show the infected areas using a heatmap with the help of machine learning. Learned to embed a Machine Learning Model into a Web Application using Flask and deploy it on a live server.

Dog Breed Identifier (Deep Learning Model)

This is a deep learning model which takes a photo image of a dog as an input, and outputs the breed of the dog and the accuracy with the help of TensorFlow and ImageNet.

Learned to make predictions using classes of images.

Sentiment Analysis (ML Model)

This is a machine learning model which takes a sentence as the input and predicts the sentiment (positive / negative) of the person writing that sentence using neural networks.

Programming Skills

Languages	Python, C/C++, Java, Dart
Machine Learning	TensorFlow, PyTorch, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Matplotlib, NumPy
App Development	Flutter
Web Development	HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Flask
Database	SQL
Linux	Terminal Commands

Additional Details

- Proficient in English, Kannada, Hindi and Telugu.
- Strong work ethics, extremely organised, attention to detail, driven by challenge, change and success, devoted to innovation, problem solver, committed to quality, adaptable/flexible, and strong sense of self-motivation.

Relevant Coursework

Data Structures and Applications Design and Analysis of Algorithms Database Management Systems Computer Networks

Online Courses (MOOCs)

- Udemy Natural Language Processing Udemy SQL Udemy AWS Associate*

- SoloLearn Python for Data Science
- SoloLearn Machine Learning*

Discrete Mathematical Structures Artificial Intelligence Data Mining and Data Warehousing Engineering Mathematics I - IV

^{*} indicates ongoing courses